

Design Leader, Design Practitioner, and Design Educator

I'm a design leader with experience managing, teaching, and mentoring designers, with the practitioner skills to deliver quality products. I also have background in startup consulting, web development, media production, and IT administration.

Experience

User Experience Design Manager • 2019 - Present

Indeed · Tokyo, Japan

- Managed design responsibilities and established operations across multiple new international market and growth teams.
- Coordinating with (and travel to) core teams in multiple locations to account for international teams' scopes touching upon majority of Indeed's product portfolio.

Lead Senior User Experience Designer • 2017 - 2019

Amazon · Seattle, United States

- Established operations for 15-20 person team, including team communications, design reviews, asset management, team documentation, services administration, etc.
- Managed, mentored, and hired designers and external vendors. Oversaw design work and project roadmaps to align designs with business and design strategy.
- Project managed design system framework, tracking design and development progress across multiple products and platforms.
- Delivered designs for Amazon Photos on iOS, Android, web, and Fire/Echo devices.

Co-Founder and Startup Consultant • 2016 - 2017

Kismet Design • San Francisco, United States

- Established startup design teams through freelancer staffing and design consultation.
- Managed business operations and mentoring of 15+ freelance designer community.

Lead User Experience Designer • 2015 - 2016

OpenTable • San Francisco, United States

- · Led design on Guest Center and Connect restaurant products for web and iPad.
- Managed design team operations for 6+ designers in two locations, including team meetings/processes, shared team assets/documentation, and design system progress.

Lead Instructor, User Experience Design • 2014 - 2017

General Assembly • San Francisco, United States

- Founding instructor of 400-hour User Experience Design Immersive course. Created curriculum, processes, and instructional practices used in over 25 locations worldwide.
- Taught courses, trained instructors, gave guest talks, and mentored designers.

Senior User Experience Designer • 2013 - 2014

Climate Corporation • San Francisco, United States

- Sole interaction designer, info architect, and researcher for web, iOS, and Android.
- Delivered designs for agriculture insurance and operation management products.
- Led full re-architecture of Climate.com, major factor in acquisition for \$1.3b USD.

User Experience Designer and Usability Specialist • 2010 - 2011

Creative Services • Bloomington, Indiana, United States

- Designed for education institutions, non-profits, and government clients.
- Conducted in-person and remote usability studies of up to 50 users for clients.

User Experience Designer • 2009 - 2010

Slingshot Labs • Los Angeles, United States

• Designed and researched for social media projects for tech incubator.

Contact

leonardpak.com linkedin.com/in/leonardpak leo@leonardpak.com +81 090-6747-7978

Other Experience

Design Mentorship • 2011-Present

Have mentored over 50 designers through design schools, graduate programs, and networking.

Freelance Design/Consulting • 2011-2017

PVComplete (2016), Candy House (2014-2015), Indiana University (2012), Amway (2011), and more.

Design, Development, IT Gigs · 2000-2010

Web/graphic design, web development, audio/video production, database management, IT administration, and technical support for various non-profits.

Education

MS, Human-Computer Interaction Design Indiana University, Bloomington

BA, East Asian Cultures

University of California, Irvine

Tools

Figma, Sketch, InVision, Principle, Flinto, Axure, Photoshop, Illustrator, Keynote

UserTesting, UserZoom, Silverback, Typeform, Ethn.io

G Suite, Quip, Asana, Basecamp, JIRA, Trello, GitHub

Languages

English (native), Japanese (elementary), Mandarin Chinese (elementary), Korean (elementary),